THE BRIDGE TO PEACE
♪～
（小南）逃がさない。
I won't let you get away!
時空間移動は失敗のようね。
Your teleportation failed.
あなたの隣に
今まで　ただいたわけではない。
I've been paying attention
to you all this time.
あなたは己を吸い込むとき
必ず体が実体化する。
When you suck in yourself,
you always materialize yourself.
そして　それは自分以外のものを
吸い込むときより遅い。
And it takes longer to suck yourself in
than another person or object.
（マダラ）時空間で飛ぶのを止めて→
If I didn't stop teleporting and shift
to the side to evade the explosion,
爆発をすり抜けるほうへ
シフトしなければ→
確かに　やばかったかもな。
things would've turned nasty.
《そして　あなたが物質を→
Furthermore, you are only able
すり抜けて
いられる時間は約５分》
to pass through objects
for five minutes!
これは…。
What are these?
ほぼすべてが起爆札。
They're all Paper Bombs…
あなたを殺すために
用意した　この６千億枚の起爆札。
I amassed 600 billion Paper Bombs
in order to kill you…
１０分間　起爆し続ける。
And they will continue to
explode for ten minutes!
((暁を弥彦に立ち上げるように
仕向けたのは俺だ。
I am the one who encouraged Yahiko
to establish the Akatsuki.
(輪廻眼を長門に与えたのも俺だ))
And I was also the one who
gave Nagato the Rinnegan.
Both Yahiko and Nagato were
acting on their own free will.
《小南：弥彦も長門も
己の考えで動いた》
《小南：彼らは
あなたのコマなんかじゃない》
They were not your pawns!
((弥彦：小南と
なんとしてでも生き延びろ))
You and Konan must do
everything you can to survive!
《小南：どんなかたちであれ→
Whichever way they chose…
They both fought and died
following their beliefs!
己の意志のために戦って死んだ。
だからこそ
その意志は繋がっている。
That is why their will is connected!
邪魔はさせない！》
I will not let you interfere!
《神の紙者の術が解けた。
My Sacred Paper Emissary Jutsu
has come undone.
ここまでのチャクラが
必要になるとは思わなかったけど。
I didn't expect it to take
this much chakra.
これで…》
At least…
マダラは確実に…。
Madara is…
死んだかな。
…Is dead?
♪～
How? You should be dead.
どうして　確実に死んだはず…。
何度もシュミレーションして→
I ran the simulations over and over.
この手順なら
あなたを倒せたはずなのに。
I was sure this sequence
would work.
イザナギ。
光を失うことと引き換えに→
The Izanagi…
In exchange for losing sight
in that eye,
a user can tie the illusion
and reality together.
幻と現実を
繋げることができるうちはの禁術。
It's a Forbidden Jutsu
of the Uchiha.
うちはと千手。
Only those who possess both the powers
of the Uchiha and Senju
この両方の力を持つ者だけが
許される瞳術。
can use this Forbidden Jutsu!
うちはと千手　両方の力。
Uchiha and Senju?
Both powers?
それは六道の力。
But that's the power
of the Six Paths.
あなたにそんな力は…。
You do not have that power…
ククク…　かつては仲間。
Since you are a dear
and former comrade,
そのよしみとして少し俺の術と
俺自身について教えてやろう。
I will tell you a little about
my jutsu and myself.
イザナギとは本来→
The Izanagi jutsu is simply
the practical application
お前の言う六道仙人の
万物創造を応用した術のことだ。
of what you already know
as the Sage of Six Paths'
Creation of all Things.
もともとは
うちはと千手はひとつだ。
Originally, the Uchiha and Senju
were one and the same.
The Sage of the Six Paths
was their founder
その２つの始祖である
六道仙人は→
and he passed on his blood
and power to these two.
その２つの血と力を持ち
あらゆるものを創った。
He also created many things.
創造を司る
精神エネルギーをもととする陰遁の力。
The Power of the Shadow Style,
based upon mental energies
that control imagination
that can be used to create
form out of nothing.
And the Power of the Light Style,
それらを使って無から形を作り→
based upon physical energies that
生命を司る
身体エネルギーをもととする陽遁の力。
govern life that could be used
to instill life into those forms.
それを使って形に命を吹き込む。
尾獣たちも　そのひとつ。
The Tailed Beasts are
one such example.
He used the Powers of
the Shadow and Light Styles
十尾のチャクラが陰陽遁の力を使い
各尾獣を創りだした。
to create the Tailed Beasts from
the chakra of the Ten Tails.
想像を生命へと具現化する術
それが　イザナギ。
The incarnation of imagination
into life…
that is the jutsu known as Izanagi.
Just who are you?
あなたは　いったい何者なの？
うちはマダラは　世間では
千手柱間に負けたとされている。
The world knows Madara Uchiha
was the one
who lost to Hashirama Senju.
However, what is the real truth?
しかし真実は　どうなのか？
The victor is the one
who can gaze into the future.
勝者とは先を見据えた者。
本当の勝負は　これから。
The real challenge begins from now.
The previous battle was merely
to obtain his power.
かつての戦いは
ヤツの力を手に入れるためのもの。
俺は　千手柱間の力を手に入れた
うちはマダラを→
I am Madara Uchiha and I possess
the power of Senju Hashirama.
２人目の六道にして
今は唯一の存在。
I am the second
Sage of the Six Paths.
I am unique.
柱間の力を制御できず→
Unable to master Hashirama's power,
some have tried to use
an imperfect Izanagi, and failed.
不完全なイザナギを披露した輩は
数いたが…。
うっ…。
ぐっ…　あっ…。
In the afterlife,
the two of you can commiserate…
向こうに行ったら
２人で後悔するといい。
about being fooled
by Naruto's nonsense.
ナルトの戯れ言にのせられたことを。
There is no such thing
as true peace!
本当の平和などない！
There is no such thing as hope!
希望などありはしない。
長門は　ナルトを信じることで→
Nagato only believed in Naruto
because he wanted
to find solace within
his pathetic existence.
哀れだった自分を
慰めたかっただけだ。
あっ！
《これは　まさか…》
This can't be…
Nagato is going to be
the bridge to peace.
((弥彦：長門は…　アイツは
平和への懸け橋になる男だ。
My job is to be a pillar
that supports that bridge.
俺の役目は
その橋を支える柱になることだ。
He is the bridge to peace.
His will itself is the bridge.
（長門）平和の懸け橋は彼だよ。
彼の意志そのものがね。
俺の役目は
ここまでのようだ　ナルト。
I guess this is
as far as it goes for me.
Naruto…I know you can truly—
(お前だったら本当は…))
The rain in the Hidden Rain
is never ending…
（マダラ）止むことのない雨隠れの雨が
どうしたことか…。
What's going on?
弥彦　長門　彼らの意志は消えない。
Yahiko! Nagato!
Your will shall not be extinguished!
私もナルトを信じてる。
I too believe in Naruto!
It's his turn now!
今度は彼が
平和の懸け橋になる男だと！
He is the bridge to peace!
And I shall be his pillar!
そして私は　そのための柱となる！
《ありがとう　長門。
Thank you, Nagato.
死んでなお
私に希望を見せてくれて》
You death has made my dream
even clearer to me.
I am expendable, a mere flower.
私は散ってもいい花。
ここであなたを！
I shall take you with me.
はっ！
♪～
お前は
俺のことを闇だと言ったな？
You called me darkness.
（マダラ）なら　俺がお前を枯らせる！
Well then, I shall make you wilt.
And I shall also make your rainbow,
そして　７色に輝く
この虹の懸け橋とやらも→
this seven-colored bridge of peace,
fade into the darkness as well.
闇の中に消してやろう。
When this genjutsu is over,
it will be the end of you too.
幻術をかけ終わったとき
お前も終わる。
After I make you tell me
where the Rinnegan is.
輪廻眼の場所を
吐かせてからだがな。
ここか。
So this is the place…
お前は　３人目の六道。
You are the third
Sage of the Six Paths.
うずまき一族　末裔の証しである
赤い髪…。
The red hair that was once proof
of your Uzumaki lineage…
それが白に変色するほどの力を…。
turned white from exerting
a power so strong.
裏切って　なお　俺を笑うか。
You betrayed me,
and still you laugh at me?
少し手間取ったな。　行くか。
That took some time.
I should go.
((自来也：いちばん右が小南。
NAGATO               YAHIKO               KONAN
The one on the right is Konan's.
中央が弥彦。
NAGATO               YAHIKO               KONAN
The one in the center is Yahiko's.
Nagato's is on the left.
で　左が長門のものだ。
（弥彦）なんだ？　それ。
（自来也）これは　かえる板という。
What are they?
These are flip tiles.
かえる板？
うむ。
Flip tiles?
Yes.
これは　表は赤
裏は白になっていて→
The top is red and
the bottom is white.
このように　板は　ひっくり返る。
And you flip the tiles
over like this!
まぁ　とにかく　アジトの中に
いるときは　板を赤にし→
Anyway, when we're at the hideout,
the tile will show red.
外出するときは
これをひっくり返して→
NAGATO               YAHIKO               KONAN
When we're going out,
flip it to the white side…
白にしてから　出かける。
NAGATO               YAHIKO               KONAN
then set out.
ちなみに　この絵は　もうすぐ帰る
と　いう合図になっている。
Furthermore, this picture is a signal
that you'll be returning shortly.
いや　なんなんすか？　さっきから。
Man, what's with all this anyway?
ガマ仙人だから
大目に見てるだけっすよ。
We're only listening to this flip stuff
because you're the Toad Sage.
このかえる押し。
でも　なんで　そんなこと　しないと
ダメなんですか？
But why is it necessary
to do all this?
このあたりは　まだ　治安も悪い。
This area is still politically unstable.
いつ　この場所が
狙われるかも　わからん。
There's no telling when
it will be targeted.
実はな　アジトにいるときが
いちばん　狙われやすい。
Actually, being at the hideout
makes us easy marks.
居場所が　バレバレの分
奇襲などを　かけやすいからのう。
If we're all scattered,
we can counter,
with a surprise attack, for example.
つまり　板が赤のままなのに→
So if the tile is red,
but someone's not at the hideout,
アジトに　その人がいないときは
敵にさらわれたとか…。
it could mean the enemy
has kidnapped them.
白なのに
部屋に　ずっといるってことは→
But if they're here and it's white,
変化した敵って可能性も
考えられる。
could mean it's a transformed enemy.
そういうのが
すぐに　わかるってことでしょ？
It's so we'll be able to recognize
things like that right away, correct?
まぁ　そんなところだ。
よく理解してるのう　小南。
Something like that.
You're very sharp, Konan.
Unlike Yahiko.
弥彦と違うて。
お…　俺だって
わかってましたよ！
I figured it out too!
なんとなくだけどな。
More or less…
フフフフフ！
（長門）フフフ…。
とにかく　４人だけの暗号として→
Anyway, this will be a secret code
between the four of us
各々　存在確認を
常に意識しておく。
to make sure we're aware
of each other at all times.
つまり　アジトにいるときも
気が抜けない状況だってことだ。
Even if we're at the hideout,
we must be vigilant!
更に！
Furthermore…
一応　地下の隠し部屋と→
I constructed
a hidden underground room
そこから外に出る抜け道も
作っておいた。
that has an escape route outside.
おぉ～　忍っぽいっす！
Wow, that's so shinobi!
（自来也）何かあったときは
ここから逃げろ。
If anything happens,
use it to get away.
あ～　ちなみに
お前らの後ろにあるのが→
Oh, and by the way…
The tile behind you is…
わしの板だ！
JIRAIYA
…is my tile.
さて　では　そろそろ
かえるの面に水の修業に→
Now then…
Shall we begin our
"Water in a Frog's Face" training?
行くとするかのう。
かえるになりきり→
This will hone your ability to
completely become a frog
何事にも動じない忍耐を
鍛える修業だ！
and stay absolutely still,
no matter what happens.
よっしゃ～！
All right!
さっさと行こうぜ　みんな！
Let's get going, everyone!
弥彦…　ホントにわかってんのかな？
I wonder if Yahiko is getting all this?
今回は　さっき
先生がやっててくれたけど…。
Sensei just showed us what to do.
俺はもっともっと強くなって
そんでもって…。
I want to become stronger!
And then…
そんでもって　この国を変える！
And then,
I'm going to change the world!
♪～
国を変える前に　まず
かえる板を引っくり返せのう！
Before you change the world,
you must change
the side on the flip tile!
《わしもさっき
あんな顔しとったのかのう…。
Did I look like that earlier too?
That's embarrassing.
いや　恥ずかしいのう》
NAGATO             YAHIKO            KONAN
やっ！
《ほお…　紙手裏剣を
風遁で加速させてきたか。
Oh? She used the Wind Style to
speed up her Paper Shuriken.
しかし…》
However…
（弥彦）だ～っ！！
しまっ…。
Damn it!
まだまだだな。
No good.
連係のタイミングを　もっと早めるんだ。
You have get quicker with
timing your coordination!
NAGATO            YAHIKO                KONAN
（自来也）いただきま～す！
Let's eat!
（３人）いただきます！
– Let's eat!
ハハハ。
あっ！　先生　ずるいぞ。
Hey! No fair, Sensei!
（自来也）うん？　そうか？
（弥彦）それ　俺の！
Oh yeah, is that so?
That's mine!
JIRAIYA
ありがとう　先生。
Thank you, Sensei.
♪～
NAGATO           YAHIKO                KONAN
（半蔵）お前たちが　暁だな？
Are you the Akatsuki?
（長門）あれは…。
Who's that?
The chief of the Hidden Rain,
Hanzo of the Salamander…
（弥彦）雨隠れの長　山椒魚の半蔵。
（半蔵）リーダーは　誰だ？
Who's the leader?
弥彦だ。　暁の弥彦。
It's Yahiko!
Yahiko of the Akatsuki!
覚えておこう。
I shall remember you.
弥彦？
どういうこと？
Yahiko?
What does that mean?
半蔵も　俺たちに
一目置いたっていうことだ。
Hanzo just acknowledged us.
NAGATO            YAHIKO          KONAN
（弥彦）組織も大きくなってきた。
Our organization is getting larger.
We need to move our hideout.
アジトも移らないとな。
（小南）こことも今日でお別れね。
ああ。
It's our last day here.
Yes.
ここで　俺たちは変わった。
This place changed us.
力をつけた。
すべては　ここから始まった。
We became strong.
Everything began right here.
俺たちは　夢の実現のために
ここより出発する。
We are leaving this place in order
to make our dreams come true!
そして…。
And…
どこへ行った？
Where did they go?
（長門）隠し部屋が
最後で役に立つとはね。
To think the secret room
would come in handy at the very end.
とんだ出発になっちまったけど
この国らしい感じだな。
What a way to set out…
But I guess,
it's appropriate for this country.
さあ　行くぞ。　長門　小南！
Let's go, Nagato! Konan!
（弥彦）俺たちは　夢の実現のために
ここより出発する。
We are leaving this place{
そして　俺たちの夢が叶ったら→
たとえ　バラバラに
なっていたとしても→
いつか　ここへ帰ってこよう。
そして　３人で祝福すんだ。
（長門）ああ。　なら　そのときは
自来也先生も　ここに呼ばなきゃ。
（小南）そうだね。
（弥彦）ま　そうなるか。
（カブト）てこずっただけあって
いい眼を手に入れたね。
あれは　もともと俺のものだ。
（ゼツ）ほら　これも届いたことだし。
それは？
鬼鮫からの情報だよ。
九尾の居場所も　わかった。
いろいろと状況は
こちらに傾いている。
へぇ…　これが鬼鮫から。
九尾を取りにいく。
（リー）うお～っ！！
ホップ　ステップ…。
ジャンプ！
見ていてくれてますか？　サクラさん。
どうです？
（ネジ）ファウル。
[スピーカ]皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。